export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2007 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. A necessary characteristic of a constitution is that it must",
A: "be a written document.",
B: "be difficult to amend.",
C: "define the various offices in the state.",
D: "be signed by members of parliament.",
answer: "C. define the various offices in the state",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The judiciary is mainly concerned with the",
A: "execution of the law.",
B: "preservation of public morality.",
C: "initiation of the law.",
D: "interpretation of the law.",
answer: "D. interpretation of the law",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. For a right to be enjoyed by a citizen he must be",
A: "taught in schools.",
B: "supported by the ruling group.",
C: "accepted by all citizens.",
D: "enforceable by a court of law.",
answer: "D. enforceable by a court of law",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. The term autocracy means",
A: "dictatorship.",
B: "monarchy.",
C: "oligarchy.",
D: "democracy.",
answer: "A. dictatorship",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Laissez-faire has been associated with",
A: "socialism.",
B: "communism.",
C: "capitalism.",
D: "totalitarianism.",
answer: "B. communism",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. Which of the following is not a necessary feature of democracy?",
A: "The rule of law",
B: "A two-tier legislature",
C: "Periodic election",
D: "Separation of powers",
answer: "B. A two-tier legislature",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. In Ghanaian traditional society, marriage serve the purpose of uniting the",
A: "families of the spouses",
B: "husband and wife only.",
C: "nuclear family.",
D: "entire society.",
answer: "A. families of the spouses",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. To accomplish a task successfully, the individual, above all, needs",
A: "self-reliance.",
B: "self-esteem.",
C: "indulgence.",
D: "determination.",
answer: "D. determination",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. The potential of the individual is best developed through",
A: "family financial support.",
B: "ingenuity and creativity.",
C: "education and training.",
D: "guidance and counselling.",
answer: "C. education and training",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. Which of the following agencies helps to socialize the individual formally into the society?",
A: "Home",
B: "School",
C: "Community",
D: "Church",
answer: "A. Home",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. Which of the following best explains socialization?",
A: "Bringing people together for friendship",
B: "Inter-marriage among different groups of people",
C: "Passing on culture from one generation to another",
D: "Bringing technology from one place to another",
answer: "C. Passing on culture from one generation to another",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. Which of the following regulates human behaviour in the traditional society?",
A: "Norms and values",
B: "By-laws",
C: "Codified laws",
D: "Decrees and edicts",
answer: "A. Norms and values",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. In Ghana, the celebration of traditional festivals always brings about the following benefits except",
A: "socialization.",
B: "free medical care.",
C: "tourism.",
D: "mobilization of funds.",
answer: "B. free medical care",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Apart from blood ties one can become a member of a family through",
A: "abduction",
B: "socialization.",
C: "friendship.",
D: "adoption.",
answer: "D. adoption",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Parent-child conflict is minimized when the parent",
A: "reports the child to religious authorities.",
B: "reprimands the child instantly.",
C: "listens to the child’s view.",
D: "reports the child to school authorities.",
answer: "C. listens to the child's view",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. The most cherished values expected of an adolescent in any given society is",
A: "patience.",
B: "chastity.",
C: "honesty.",
D: "hospitality.",
answer: "B. chastity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Fertilization in humans occurs in the",
A: "ovary.",
B: "cervix.",
C: "fallopian tubes.",
D: "vagina",
answer: "C. fallopian tubes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Parenthood begins as soon as a child",
A: "is conceived.",
B: "is born.",
C: "is named.",
D: "starts schooling.",
answer: "A. is conceived",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. Which of the following can least pollute water bodies?",
A: "Solid waste",
B: "Oil spillage",
C: "Acid",
D: "Bush fire",
answer: "D. Bush fire",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. The ozone layer is found in the",
A: "ionosphere.",
B: "mesosphere.",
C: "stratosphere.",
D: "atmosphere.",
answer: "C. stratosphere",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. One major implication of the structure of Ghana’s population is",
A: "inadequate amenities for the people.",
B: "high dependency burden.",
C: "high birth rate.",
D: "increase in fertility.",
answer: "B. high dependency burden",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. All the following were factors which influenced the migration of the major ethnic groups to Ghana except the",
A: "use of common language.",
B: "quest for fertile land.",
C: "desire for lucrative trade.",
D: "quest for peace and security",
answer: "A. use of common language",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. Non-material culture includes all the following except",
A: "language.",
B: "customs.",
C: "clothing.",
D: "religion.",
answer: "C. clothing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. The most common agricultural practice in Ghana is",
A: "fish farming.",
B: "peasant farming",
C: "pastoral farming.",
D: "plantation farming",
answer: "B. peasant farming",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Which of the following accounts for the higher productivity in the private sector?  \nI.	Better supervision  \nII.	Bureaucracy  \nIII.	Fear of losing one’s job  \nIV.	Provision of needed facilities",
A: "I, and II only",
B: "I, III and IV only.",
C: "II, III and lV only",
D: "II, and IV only",
answer: "B. I, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. One sure way of raising the per capita income of Ghana is to",
A: "go in for foreign loans.",
B: "import more foreign goods.",
C: "give workers higher wages.",
D: "increase productivity.",
answer: "D. increase productivity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. Ghana has co-operation agreements with all the following organizations except",
A: "American Peace Corps.",
B: "Voluntary Services Overseas.",
C: "North Atlantic Treaty Organization.",
D: "German Technical Co-operation.",
answer: "C. North Atlantic Treaty Organization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. The youth can enhance the development of a nation when given",
A: "enough money.",
B: "the necessary education and guidance.",
C: "unrestricted freedom.",
D: "charge of leadership positions.",
answer: "B. the necessary education and guidance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Nation-building is basically concerned with",
A: "development of social infrastructure.",
B: "human resource development.",
C: "international security and harmony.",
D: "social integration, peace and stability.",
answer: "D. social integration, peace and stability",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Scientific knowledge is based on",
A: "tested facts.",
B: "traditional beliefs.",
C: "one’s instinct.",
D: "religious beliefs.",
answer: "A. tested facts",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Which of the following is not applicable to foreigners in Ghana?",
A: "Right to education",
B: "Right to privacy",
C: "Right to vote",
D: "Right to property",
answer: "C. Right to vote",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. The Intestate Succession Law mainly seeks to protect the",
A: "members of the extended family.",
B: "surviving spouse and children.",
C: "surviving parents of the deceased.",
D: "customary laws of the clan.",
answer: "B. surviving spouse and children",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. The current upsurge in indiscipline in schools can best be brought under control through",
A: "indefinite suspension",
B: "guidance and counselling.",
C: "outright dismissal",
D: "corporal punishment",
answer: "B. guidance and counselling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. Which of these pairs of concepts are regarded as opposite sides of the same coin in a democratic country?",
A: "Rights and responsibilities",
B: "The judiciary and the executive",
C: "Freedoms and rights",
D: "The government and the presidency",
answer: "A. Rights and responsibilities",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. An economy that works effectively and brings about improvement in the quality of life of the people is described as",
A: "traditional.",
B: "buoyant.",
C: "developing.",
D: "centralized.",
answer: "B. buoyant",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The main feature of duo local marriage is that the couple",
A: "live with the wife’s family.",
B: "live in the husband’s father’s compound.",
C: "continue to live separately in their natal homes.",
D: "live with the wife’s kin group.",
answer: "C. continue to live separately in their natal homes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Which of the following is not an objective for setting up a private business?",
A: "Providing goods and services in the community",
B: "Making workers more efficient",
C: "Generating profit for the owner",
D: "Creating employment for the youth",
answer: "B. Making workers more efficient",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. Which of the following is not a leadership style?",
A: "Paternalism",
B: "Autocracy",
C: "Democracy",
D: "Presidency",
answer: "D. Presidency",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. To ensure national integration in Ghana",
A: "membership of political parties should cut across ethnic boundaries.",
B: "the president should be elected by the various ethnic groups on rotational basis",
C: "all districts should have equal representation in parliament.",
D: "the constitution should be amended from time to time.",
answer: "A. membership of political parties should cut across ethnic boundaries",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. Which of the following practices is not included in preparing a girl for marriage in the Ghanaian traditional society?",
A: "Puberty rites",
B: "Ancestral worship",
C: "Purification rites",
D: "Initiation rites",
answer: "B. Ancestral worship",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Post-harvest losses suffered by Ghanaian farmers can be minimized by providing them with",
A: "credit facilities",
B: "storage facilities.",
C: "extension services",
D: "new farming techniques",
answer: "B. storage facilities",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. The policy of decentralization in public administration is mainly aimed at",
A: "giving employment to local people.",
B: "allowing communities to take their own initiatives.",
C: "preventing rural-urban drift",
D: "strengthening the finances of traditional authorities",
answer: "B. allowing communities to take their own initiatives",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Which of the following international organizations contributes a great deal in offering scholarships to Ghanaian students?",
A: "The Non-Aligned Movement (N.A.M.)",
B: "The United Nations Organization (U.N.0.)",
C: "The African Union(A.U.)",
D: "The Economic Community of West African States (E.C.O.W.A.S.)",
answer: "B. The United Nations Organization (U",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. Under the constitution of the Third Republic of Ghana, the President was",
A: "appointed by the Supreme Court.",
B: "elected by members of parliament.",
C: "elected by popular vote.",
D: "selected by the Council of State.",
answer: "C. elected by popular vote",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. To execute a law is to",
A: "test if it can be broken.",
B: "pass it.",
C: "amend it.",
D: "put it into effect.",
answer: "D. put it into effect",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. The means by which people use knowledge to produce goods and services is called",
A: "science",
B: "technology",
C: "philosophy",
D: "ingenuity",
answer: "B. technology",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. The economic term for material resource other than land is",
A: "labour.",
B: "entrepreneurship.",
C: "capital",
D: "expertise.",
answer: "C. capital",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. Ghana is classified as a less- developed country in the world because of her low",
A: "population growth rate",
B: "level of illiteracy",
C: "level of mining.",
D: "per capita income",
answer: "D. per capita income",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Secondary production involves",
A: "the use of machines to add value to goods.",
B: "extraction of goods from natural resources.",
C: "rendering services to people.",
D: "distribution of goods.",
answer: "A. the use of machines to add value to goods",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. The production process ends with the",
A: "consumer.",
B: "producer.",
C: "retailer.",
D: "wholesaler.",
answer: "A. consumer",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question51",
question: "51. Poor attitude towards work can best be minimized through",
A: "outright dismissals.",
B: "effective supervision.",
C: "constant persuasion.",
D: "regular annual leave.",
answer: "B. effective supervision",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question52",
question: "52. Under which sector of production can we classify the activities of teachers, doctors and engineers?",
A: "Primary",
B: "Secondary",
C: "Tertiary",
D: "Industrial",
answer: "C. Tertiary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question53",
question: "53. The facility offered a customer to take more money than what is in his/her bank account is known as",
A: "a standing order.",
B: "a payment order.",
C: "a debenture.",
D: "an overdraft.",
answer: "D. an overdraft",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question54",
question: "54. Which of the following business units is set up for the ultimate welfare of the people?",
A: "Sole proprietorship",
B: "Partnership",
C: "State-owned enterprise.",
D: "Joint-stock company",
answer: "C. State-owned enterprise",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question55",
question: "55. What a business owes to creditors is known as",
A: "assets.",
B: "capital.",
C: "sales.",
D: "liabilities.",
answer: "D. liabilities",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question56",
question: "56. Sustainable development can best be achieved in a country by",
A: "foreign aid.",
B: "political stability.",
C: "debt cancellation.",
D: "abundant natural resources.",
answer: "B. political stability",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question57",
question: "57. Nation-building can best be promoted when a leader",
A: "is friendly with his followers.",
B: "shares authority with his followers.",
C: "is selfless and permissive.",
D: "has vision and initiative.",
answer: "D. has vision and initiative",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question58",
question: "58. In the traditional society the main expectation of marriage is",
A: "companionship.",
B: "sexual satisfaction.",
C: "procreation.",
D: "support",
answer: "C. procreation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question59",
question: "59. One of the characteristics of a monarchy is the59. One of the characteristics of a monarchy is the",
A: "tradition of inheriting political office.",
B: "attainment of political office by election.",
C: "appointment to political office by an electoral college.",
D: "seizure of political office by force.",
answer: "A. tradition of inheriting political office",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question60",
question: "60. For a representative democracy to exist",
A: "voting should be made compulsory.",
B: "closure of some local industries",
C: "the right to vote should be universal",
D: "people should vote along ethnic lines",
answer: "C. the right to vote should be universal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]